Yuliia Tkachenko

FRONT END DEVELOPER

+1 (778) 957 63 12 | ecspetra@gmail.com | Vancouver, BC, Canada | www.linkedin.com/in/tkachenko-yuliia-v

SUMMARY

I have over 2 years of experience in front-end development and more than 4 years of experience in UI/UX design. Since the beginning of my journey as a developer, I have worked on a wide variety of tasks both by myself and in collaboration with talented people. I have experience in development of web applications, landing pages, corporate websites. Also I have portfolio with my own projects vuliia-tkachenko.dev

SKILLS

Next.js, TypeScript, React, JavaScript, Redux, Redux Toolkit, Git, HTML, CSS, SASS, Tailwind, Bootstrap, WordPress, BEM, JQuery, JIRA, Photoshop, Figma, Firebase

WORK EXPERIENCE

Swivl | Menlo Park, USA

12.2021 - 09.2023

Front End Developer

Worked on the development of a productivity tool designed for finding focus and enhancing the optimal learning experience.

- Developed project's interface with React components and SCSS, ensuring seamless functionality, responsive design, and user-friendly interfaces
- Proposed and implemented some solutions to improve the visual component of the project and user experience
- Developed landing pages and maintained WordPress website
- Designed and styled email templates for marketing campaigns

Tech stack: React, TypeScript, HTML, SASS, Git, WordPress

Livelib | Ukraine 08.2021 – 12.2021

Front End Developer

Worked on a high-loaded project with over than 3 millions monthly users.

- Implemented SASS technology for more efficient use of styles on the project
- Refactored all styles on the project to make it perform faster
- Suggested and implemented images and SVG files compression on the project
- Developed commercial advertising projects, landing pages
- Developed corporate websites

Tech stack: JavaScript, JQuery, HTML, CSS, SASS, Git

Byte | Ukraine 01.2021 – 02.2021

Volunteer

Worked as a mentor in an IT school for children.

- Developed manuals for teaching children programming and UI/UX design
- Successfully managed multiple projects simultaneously, meeting deadlines and exceeding client expectations

Tech stack: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Illustrator, Photoshop, Figma

Livelib | Ukraine 07.2017 - 01.2021 UI/UX Designer

Worked as UI/UX designer on social network, created as a platform for famous book writers.

- Developed design for banners, landing pages, corporate websites, advertisement, mailing lists
- Successfully managed multiple projects simultaneously, meeting deadlines and exceeding client expectations

Tech stack: Photoshop, Illustrator, Figma

EDUCATION

Master of Computer Science

Pryazovskyi State Technical University, Mariupol, Ukraine

2019